JUAN CARLOS ALONSO VALENZUELA

PhD Student

www.javalenzuela.com

javalenzuela@us.es

PROFILE

23-year-old PhD Student in Software Engineering, with a master's degree in Software Engineering (CLOUD, Data, and IT Management) and a bachelor's degree in Software Engineering. I am currently working as a teaching assistant in the University of Seville. My current research interests focus on automated software engineering, software testing, natural language processing, and artificial intelligence.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

POSITIONS

•	Predoctoral researcher	2022
	Applied Software Engineering (ISA) research group – Seville (Spain)	
•	Teaching assistant	2021
	University of Seville (Spain)	
•	Research assistant	2020 - 2021
	Applied Software Engineering (ISA) research group – Seville (Spain)	

PUBLICATIONS

Journals

Juan C. Alonso, Alberto Martin-Lopez, Sergio Segura, José María García, Antonio Ruiz-Cortés.
 ARTE: Automated Generation of Realistic Test Inputs for Web APIs. IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering. 2022.

Conferences and workshops

- Juan C. Alonso. **Automated Generation of Test Oracles for RESTful APIs.** *30th ACM Joint Meeting on European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering, ACM Student Research Competition (ESEC/FSE 2022).* Singapore. 2022.
- Sergio Segura, Juan C. Alonso, Alberto Martin-Lopez, Amador Durán, Javier Troya, Antonio Ruiz-Cortés. Automated Generation of Metamorphic Relations for Query-Based Systems. 7th International Workshop on Metamorphic Testing (MET'22). Pittsburgh, USA. 2022.
- Juan C. Alonso. Automated generation of realistic test inputs for web APIs. 29th ACM Joint Meeting on European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering, ACM Student Research Competition (ESEC/FSE 2021). Athens, Greece. 2021.

R&D PROJECTS

National projects:

• BUBO: Improving the development, reliability and governance of digital services through bothuman collaboration.

Funding: Ministerio de Ciencia, Innovación y Universidades (Spanish Government).

Duration: 2022 - 2024 (3 years).

• HORATIO: Improvements in the reliability, customization and operating costs of software services regulated by user agreements.

Funding: Ministerio de Ciencia, Innovación y Universidades (Spanish Government).

Duration: 2019 - 2021 (3 years).

Regional projects:

• EKIPMENT-PLUS: Knowledge-based process performance improvement: A multidisciplinary empirical approach based on people, equipment, software, and data.

Funding: Junta de Andalucía (Consejería de Economía y Conocimiento) (Andalusian Government).

Duration: 2020 - 2022 (3 years).

APOLO: Technologies for highly reliable service-oriented systems regulated by user contracts.

Funding: Junta de Andalucía (Programa operativo FEDER) (Andalusian Government).

Duration: 2019 - 2021 (3 years).

ACKNOWLEDGMENTS AND AWARDS

- Winner of the ACM Student Research Competition at the European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE 2022).
- Mentee at IMFAHE (www.imfahe.org), the International Mentoring Foundation for the Advancement of Higher Education.
- Best Master Thesis of my promotion. (July 2022).
- Award for best Bachelor Thesis of my promotion. (November 2021).

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- Architecture and Integration of Software Systems. Software Engineering degree, 2nd year.
 University of Seville.
 - o 2021-2022: Laboratory sessions (English and Spanish groups).
- Data and Algorithm Analysis and Design. Software Engineering degree, 2nd year. University of Seville.
 - o 2021-2022: Laboratory sessions.
- Intelligent Access to Information. Software Engineering degree, 4th year. University of Seville.
 - o 2021-2022: Laboratory sessions.
- Operating Systems. Software Engineering degree, 2nd year. University of Seville.
 - o 2021-2022: Laboratory sessions.
- Requirements Engineering: Software Engineering degree, 3rd year. University of Seville.
 - o 2022: Laboratory sessions.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Software Engineering – CLOUD, Data and IT Management 2021 - 2022
 Escuela Técnica Superior de Ingeniería Informática (University of Seville) – Seville (Spain)

Average: 9.59 (over 10). Subjects with distinction: 5 (including thesis).

• Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering 2016 - 2021

Escuela Técnica Superior de Ingeniería Informática (University of Seville) – Seville (Spain) University of Mannheim (Germany) – Erasmus stay (2019-2020)

Average: 7.82 (over 10). Subjects with distinction: 3 (including thesis)

LANGUAGES

- Spanish. Native proficiency.
- English. Bilingual proficiency. C2 level certified by Cambridge.
- **Japanese.** Intermediate working proficiency. B1 level certified by the Institute of Languages of the University of Seville.